[{"id":1,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Ile modeli języka wchodzi w skład rodziny Qra?","answers":["0","1","2","3"],"correct":3},
{"id":2,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Ile miliardów parametrów ma największy model z rodziny Qra?","answers":["1","70","13","8"],"correct":2},
{"id":3,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Ile miliardów parametrów ma najmniejszy model z rodziny Qra?","answers":["0.5","1","1.5","3"],"correct":1},
{"id":4,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Jaka uczelnia stoi za stworzeniem modelu języka Qra?","answers":["Politechnika Gdańska","Uniwersytet Warszawski","AGH","Uniwersyste im. Adama Mickiewicza"],"correct":0},
{"id":5,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Jaka jest wielkość okna kontekstowego dla modeli języka z rodzin Qra?","answers":["2048","512","4096","1024"],"correct":2},
{"id":6,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Na jakiej licencji został udostępniony model języka Qra-1B?","answers":["Apache 2.0","MIT","LLama 2 Community License Agreement","Creative Commons"],"correct":0},
{"id":7,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Na bazie jakiego modelu języka powstał model Qra-1B?","answers":["Llama-3.2-1B","GPT-2","Mistral-7B-v0.3","TinyLlama-1.1B"],"correct":3},
{"id":8,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Ile dni zajęła nauka modelu Qra-1B?","answers":["7","1","2","5"],"correct":2},
{"id":9,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Na bazie jakiego modelu języka powstał model Qra-7B?","answers":["Mistral-7B-v0.1","Llama-2-7b-hf","Meta-Llama-3-8B","Bielik-7B-v0.1"],"correct":1}, 
{"id":10,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Na jakiej licencji został udostępniony model języka Qra-7B","answers":["GNU GPL","Qra Open-Licence","MIT","LLama 2 Community License Agreement"],"correct":3},
{"id":11,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Ile dni zajęła nauka modelu Qra-7B?","answers":["14","7","21","30"],"correct":0},
{"id":12,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Na bazie jakiego modelu języka powstał model Qra-13B?","answers":["Phi4-14B","Qwen-2.5-14B","Llama-2-13b-hf","Olmo2-13B"],"correct":2},
{"id":13,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Na jakiej licencji został udostępniony model języka Qra-13B","answers":["LLama 2 Community License Agreement","Apache License 2.0","MIT","LGPL"],"correct":0},
{"id":14,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Ile dni zajęła nauka modelu Qra-13B?","answers":["13","35","7","25"],"correct":1},
{"id":15,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Jakiego typu modelu języka są modele z rodziny Qra?","answers":["base","chat","instruct","guardrail"],"correct":0},
{"id":16,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Jaki jest główny język którym operują modele języka z rodziny Qra?","answers":["angielski","słowacki","polski","rosyjski"],"correct":2},
{"id":17,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Qra","question":"Jaki jest rozmiar ostatecznego korpusu uczęcego modele języka z rodziny Qra?","answers":["1 TB","500 GB","13 GB","2 TB"],"correct":0},
{"id":18,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Kto jest głównym właścicielem modeli języka z rodziny Bielik?","answers":["Polskie Ministerstwo Cyfryzacji","Uniwersytet im. Adama Mickiewicza","Politechnika Warszawska","SpeakLeash"],"correct":3},
{"id":19,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Jakiego typu modelem SI jest model Sójka?","answers":["embedding","guardrail","llm-instruct","llm-base"],"correct":1},
{"id":20,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Ile miliardów parametrów ma największy model z rodziny Bielik?","answers":["11","8","7","70"],"correct":0},
{"id":21,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Ile miliardów parametrów ma najmniejszy model z rodziny Bielik?","answers":["11","8","7","70"],"correct":2},
{"id":22,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Na bazie jakiego modelu języka powstał Bielik-7B-v0.1","answers":["Llama-2-7b-hf","Mistral-7B-v0.1","Qwen-2.5-14B","gemma-7b-it"],"correct":2},
{"id":23,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Na jakiej licencji został udostępniony model języka Bielik-7B-v0.1","answers":["LLama 2 Community License Agreement","Apache License 2.0","MIT","LGPL"],"correct":1},
{"id":24,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Na bazie jakiego modelu języka powstał Bielik-11B-v2","answers":["Mistral-7B-v0.2","Qwen-2.5-14B","gemma-7b-it","GPT2-xl"],"correct":0},
{"id":25,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Jaki jest główny język którym operują modele języka z rodziny Bielik?","answers":["angielski","słowacki","polski","rosyjski"],"correct":2},
{"id":26,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Na infrastruktzure jakiej uczelnii był uczony model języka Bielik?","answers":["Politechnika Gdańska","Uniwersytet Warszawski","AGH","Uniwersyste im. Adama Mickiewicza"],"correct":2},
{"id":27,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Jaka jest wielkość okna kontekstowego dla modelu języka Bielik-7B-v0.1?","answers":["2048","512","4096","1024"],"correct":2},
{"id":28,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Jaka jest wielkość okna kontekstowego dla modeli języka z rodziny Bielik-7B-v2?","answers":["32000","128000","4096","16000"],"correct":0},
{"id":29,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Jakim odel języka został zaadoptowany przez startup Gaius Lex?","answers":["Bielik","Qra","PLLuM","GPT-3"],"correct":0},
{"id":30,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Jaki model języka został zaadoptowany przez poznańską firmę DomData?","answers":["Bielik","Qra","PLLuM","GPT-3"],"correct":0},
{"id":31,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Jaki model będzie wykorzystywany w polskiej administracji publicznej?","answers":["Qra","Bielik","PLLuM","PolishRoberta"],"correct":2},
{"id":32,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Jaki jest główny język którym operuje model PLLuM?","answers":["angielski","niemiecki","polski","francuski"],"correct":2},
{"id":33,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Ile miliardów parametrów ma najmniejszy model z rodziny PLLuM","answers":["12","8","7","70"],"correct":1},
{"id":34,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Kto jest głównym właścicielem modeli z rodziny PLLuM","answers":["Polskie Ministerstwo Cyfryzacji","Uniwersytet im. Adama Mickiewicza","Politechnika Warszawska","SpeakLeash"],"correct":0},
{"id":35,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Ile miliardów parametrów ma największy model z rodziny PLLuM","answers":["12","8","7","70"],"correct":1},
{"id":36,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Jaki model języka został zaadoptowany przez firmę Comarch w ChatERP?","answers":["Bielik","Qra","PLLuM","GPT-3"],"correct":2},
{"id":37,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Na jakiej licencji został udostępniony model języka Llama-PLLuM-8B-base?","answers":["Llama 3.1","Apache License 2.0","MIT","LGPL"],"correct":0},
{"id":38,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Na jakiej licencji został udostępniony model języka PLLuM-12B-base?","answers":["Apache License 2.0","CC-BY-NC-4.0","MIT","LGPL"],"correct":1},
{"id":39,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Na jakiej licencji został udostępniony model języka PLLuM-8x7B-base?","answers":["CC-BY-NC-4.0","MIT","LGPL","Apache License 2.0"],"correct":3},
{"id":40,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Na bazie jakiego modelu języka powstał Llama-PLLuM-8B-base?","answers":["Llama3.1-8B","Mistral-7B-v0.1","Qwen-2.5-14B","gemma-7b-it"],"correct":0},
{"id":41,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Na bazie jakiego modelu języka powstał PLLuM-12B-base?","answers":["Llama-2-7b-hf","Mistral-Nemo-Base-2407","Qwen-2.5-14B","gemma-7b-it"],"correct":1},
{"id":42,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Na bazie jakiego modelu języka powstał PLLuM-8x7B-base?","answers":["Llama-2-7b-hf","Qwen-2.5-14B","Mixtral-8x7B-v0.1","gemma-7b-it"],"correct":2},
{"id":43,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Jaka uczelnia była liderem projektu PLLuM?","answers":["Politechnika Wrocławska","Uniwersytet Warszawski","AGH","Uniwersyste im. Adama Mickiewicza"],"correct":0},
{"id":44,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Jakie okno kontekstowe ma model języka Llama-PLLuM-8B-base?","answers":["1K","32K","64K","128k"],"correct":3},
{"id":45,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Jakie okno kontekstowe ma model języka PLLuM-12B-base?","answers":["1K","32K","64K","128k"],"correct":1},
{"id":46,"lang":"PL","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Jakie okno kontekstowe ma model języka PLLuM-8x7B-base?","answers":["1K","32K","64K","128k"],"correct":3},
{"id":47,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Benchmark","question":"Naukowcy z jakiego uniwerystetu w Polsce stworzyli benchmark llmzszł?","answers":["Uniwersytet Szczeciński","Uniwersytet Warszawski","Uniwersyste im. Adama Mickiewicza","Uniwersytet Jagielloński"],"correct":2},
{"id":48,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Benchmark","question":"Na jakim type danych oparty jest benchmark llmzszł?","answers":["Fake news i artykuły dezinformacyjne","Polskie egzaminy państwowe","Korpus literacki w języku polskim","Archiwalne nagrania sejmowe"],"correct":1},
{"id":49,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Benchmark","question":"Czym jest llmzsł w kotekście ewaluacji modeli języka?","answers":["benchmark","metryka ewaluacji","mały model języka","narzędzie do ewaluacji"],"correct":0},
{"id":50,"lang":"PL","qtype":"Benchmark","question":"Jaki typ zadania znjadziemy w benchmarku llmzszl?","answers":["analiza sentymentu","porównywanie podobieństwa zdań","test na kreatywność","test jednokrotnego wybóru"],"correct":3},
{"id":51,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"How many language models are part of the Qra family?","answers":["0","1","2","3"],"correct":3},
{"id":52,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"How many billion parameters does the largest model in the Qra family have?","answers":["1","70","13","8"],"correct":2},
{"id":53,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"How many billion parameters does the smallest model in the Qra family have?","answers":["0.5","1","1.5","3"],"correct":1},
{"id":54,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"Which university is behind the creation of the Qra language model?","answers":["Gdańsk University of Technology","University of Warsaw","AGH","Adam Mickiewicz University"],"correct":0},
{"id":55,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"What is the context window size for language models from the Qra family?","answers":["2048","512","4096","1024"],"correct":2},
{"id":56,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"Under which license is the Qra-1B language model released?","answers":["Apache 2.0","MIT","LLama 2 Community License Agreement","Creative Commons"],"correct":0},
{"id":57,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"Which language model was used as the base for the Qra-1B model?","answers":["Llama-3.2-1B","GPT-2","Mistral-7B-v0.3","TinyLlama-1.1B"],"correct":3},
{"id":58,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"How many days did it take to train the Qra-1B model?","answers":["7","1","2","5"],"correct":2},
{"id":59,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"Which language model was used as the base for the Qra-7B model?","answers":["Mistral-7B-v0.1","Llama-2-7b-hf","Meta-Llama-3-8B","Bielik-7B-v0.1"],"correct":1},
{"id":60,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"Under which license is the Qra-7B language model released?","answers":["GNU GPL","Qra Open-License","MIT","LLama 2 Community License Agreement"],"correct":3},
{"id":61,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"How many days did it take to train the Qra-7B model?","answers":["14","7","21","30"],"correct":0},
{"id":62,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"Which language model was used as the base for the Qra-13B model?","answers":["Phi4-14B","Qwen-2.5-14B","Llama-2-13b-hf","Olmo2-13B"],"correct":2},
{"id":63,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"Under which license is the Qra-13B language model released?","answers":["LLama 2 Community License Agreement","Apache License 2.0","MIT","LGPL"],"correct":0},
{"id":64,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"How many days did it take to train the Qra-13B model?","answers":["13","35","7","25"],"correct":1},
{"id":65,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"What type of language model are the models from the Qra family?","answers":["base","chat","instruct","guardrail"],"correct":0},
{"id":66,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"What is the main language that the language models from the Qra family operate in?","answers":["English","Slovak","Polish","Russian"],"correct":2},
{"id":67,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Qra","question":"What is the size of the final training corpus for language models from the Qra family?","answers":["1 TB","500 GB","13 GB","2 TB"],"correct":0},
{"id":68,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Who is the main owner of the language models from the Bielik family?","answers":["Polish Ministry of Digitization","Adam Mickiewicz University","Warsaw University of Technology","SpeakLeash"],"correct":3},
{"id":69,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"What type of AI model is the Sójka model?","answers":["embedding","guardrail","llm-instruct","llm-base"],"correct":1},
{"id":70,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"How many billion parameters does the largest model in the Bielik family have?","answers":["11","8","7","70"],"correct":0},
{"id":71,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"How many billion parameters does the smallest model in the Bielik family have?","answers":["11","8","7","70"],"correct":2},
{"id":72,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Which language model was used as the base for the Bielik-7B-v0.1 model?","answers":["Llama-2-7b-hf","Mistral-7B-v0.1","Qwen-2.5-14B","gemma-7b-it"],"correct":2},
{"id":73,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Under which license is the Bielik-7B-v0.1 language model released?","answers":["LLama 2 Community License Agreement","Apache License 2.0","MIT","LGPL"],"correct":1},
{"id":74,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Which language model was used as the base for the Bielik-11B-v2 model?","answers":["Mistral-7B-v0.2","Qwen-2.5-14B","gemma-7b-it","GPT2-xl"],"correct":0},
{"id":75,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"What is the main language that the language models from the Bielik family operate in?","answers":["English","Slovak","Polish","Russian"],"correct":2},
{"id":76,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Which university infrastructure was used to train the Bielik language model?","answers":["Gdańsk University of Technology","University of Warsaw","AGH","Adam Mickiewicz University"],"correct":2},
{"id":77,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"What is the context window size for the Bielik-7B-v0.1 language model?","answers":["2048","512","4096","1024"],"correct":2},
{"id":78,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"What is the context window size for the Bielik-7B-v2 language models?","answers":["32000","128000","4096","16000"],"correct":0},
{"id":79,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Which language model was adopted by the Gaius Lex startup?","answers":["Bielik","Qra","PLLuM","GPT-3"],"correct":0},
{"id":80,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Bielik","question":"Which language model was adopted by the Poznań-based company DomData?","answers":["Bielik","Qra","PLLuM","GPT-3"],"correct":0},
{"id":81,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Which model will be used in Polish public administration?","answers":["Qra","Bielik","PLLuM","PolishRoberta"],"correct":2},
{"id":82,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"What is the main language that the PLLuM model operates in?","answers":["English","German","Polish","French"],"correct":2},
{"id":83,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"How many billion parameters does the smallest model in the PLLuM family have?","answers":["12","8","7","70"],"correct":1},
{"id":84,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Who is the main owner of the models from the PLLuM family?","answers":["Polish Ministry of Digitization","Adam Mickiewicz University","Warsaw University of Technology","SpeakLeash"],"correct":0},
{"id":85,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"How many billion parameters does the largest model in the PLLuM family have?","answers":["12","8","7","70"],"correct":1},
{"id":86,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Which language model was adopted by Comarch in ChatERP?","answers":["Bielik","Qra","PLLuM","GPT-3"],"correct":2},
{"id":87,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Under which license is the Llama-PLLuM-8B-base model released?","answers":["Llama 3.1","Apache License 2.0","MIT","LGPL"],"correct":0},
{"id":88,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Under which license is the PLLuM-12B-base language model released?","answers":["Apache License 2.0","CC-BY-NC-4.0","MIT","LGPL"],"correct":1},
{"id":89,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Under which license is the PLLuM-8x7B-base language model released?","answers":["CC-BY-NC-4.0","MIT","LGPL","Apache License 2.0"],"correct":3},
{"id":90,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Which language model was used as the base for the Llama-PLLuM-8B-base model?","answers":["Llama3.1-8B","Mistral-7B-v0.1","Qwen-2.5-14B","gemma-7b-it"],"correct":0},
{"id":91,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Which language model was PLLuM-12B-base based on?","answers":["Llama-2-7b-hf","Mistral-Nemo-Base-2407","Qwen-2.5-14B","gemma-7b-it"],"correct":1},
{"id":92,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Which language model was PLLuM-8x7B-base based on?","answers":["Llama-2-7b-hf","Qwen-2.5-14B","Mixtral-8x7B-v0.1","gemma-7b-it"],"correct":2},
{"id":93,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"Which university was the leader of the PLLuM project?","answers":["Wrocław University of Technology","University of Warsaw","AGH","Adam Mickiewicz University in Poznań"],"correct":0},
{"id":94,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"What is the context window size of the Llama-PLLuM-8B-base language model?","answers":["1K","32K","64K","128K"],"correct":3},
{"id":95,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"What is the context window size of the PLLuM-12B-base language model?","answers":["1K","32K","64K","128K"],"correct":1},
{"id":96,"lang":"EN","qtype":"PLLuM","question":"What is the context window size of the PLLuM-8x7B-base language model?","answers":["1K","32K","64K","128K"],"correct":3},
{"id":97,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Benchmark","question":"Which university in Poland created the llmzszł benchmark?","answers":["University of Szczecin","University of Warsaw","Adam Mickiewicz University in Poznań","Jagiellonian University"],"correct":2},
{"id":98,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Benchmark","question":"What type of data is the llmzszł benchmark based on?","answers":["Fake news and disinformation articles","Polish state exams","Literary corpus in Polish","Archival parliamentary recordings"],"correct":1},
{"id":99,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Benchmark","question":"What is llmzsł in the context of language model evaluation?","answers":["benchmark","evaluation metric","small language model","evaluation tool"],"correct":0},
{"id":100,"lang":"EN","qtype":"Benchmark","question":"What type of task can be found in the llmzszł benchmark?","answers":["sentiment analysis","sentence similarity comparison","creativity test","single-choice test"],"correct":3}]